Amey Vijay Suryawanshi

| Github: https://github.com/AmeyS56 | ML | DSA| React.js | Node.js | Express.js

Overview

Skilled in **Data Analytics**, **SQL**, **Web Development**, **Machine Learning**, **Java**, **C/C++**, **Problem Solving** etc. I'm looking forward to working for an organization that will put my abilities and expertise to use while offering me the opportunity to learn and expand my knowledge.

Education

Vidya Pratisthan's Kamal Nayan Bajaj Institute of Engineering and Technology.

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering June 2024

CGPA: 9.32 out of 10

Vidya Pratishthan's Arts Science and Commerce

College Baramati.

HSC (Science),

June 2020

Percentage: 72.00

M.E.S. High School Baramati.
SSC,
Baramati
May 2018

Percentage: 85.60

Work Experience

1) Al and ML Intern Oct 2022 -Nov 2022

IBM

- Worked as a Data Analyst during my IBM internship. Contributed to a project focused on Breast Cancer Detection using Machine Learning.
- Collected and preprocessed large-scale breast cancer datasets. Conducted exploratory data analysis to identify patterns and trends.
- Developed predictive models using machine learning algorithms. Optimized models through feature engineering.

2) Web Development Intern

Feb 2023 - Apr 2023

Baramati

Nirmitee.io

- Worked as a Web Developer at Nirmeeti.io. Developed a full stack MERN AI Image Generator utilizing OpenAI's API. Integrated OpenAI's API to leverage its artificial intelligence capabilities.
- Utilized the MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) stack for the project. Implemented server-side functionality using Node.js and Express.js. Leveraged Atlas DB as an online cloud database for efficient data storage and retrieval.
- Designed and built the front-end using React.js for a user-friendly interface. Collaborated with a team to ensure successful integration and deployment of the application.

Projects

The Rise- Women Empowerment

- **July 2023**
- Created a HTML, CSS based website to help Womens of the country to get knowledge about laws provided by Indian Government.
- This project involved REST APIs, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Reactis and relevant skills.
- This project also provides platform to womens to register their complaint.
- This project is now handled under the guidance of Bharat Forge CSR

Spam Message detection using AIML

Oct 2022 - Nov 2022

- Created a ML based spam message detection system for detecting spam emails under IBM internship program.
- This project involved Python, Data analysis, Artificial Intelligence and relevant skills.

Al Image Generator using API's

Apr 2023

- Developed a full stack MERN AI Image Generator utilizing OpenAI's API.
- This project involved skills like MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), react.js, Atlas DB, OpenAl API.

Cancer Detection using AIML

Oct 2022

- Created a Breast Cancer detection system using AIML
- This project involved skills like python, Machine Learning, Data analysis etc.

Certifications

- Complete 2023 Web Dev Bootcamp by Dr Angela Yu (Udemy)
- The Data Science Course (Udemy)
- C++ Beginner to Advance by Abdul Bari(Udemy)
- Mastering Data Structures and Algorithm by Abdul Bari (Udemy)
- Machine Learning A-Z by kirill Eremenko (Udemy)
- Python for data Science (Coursera).
- The complete java certification course (Udemy).

Extracurricular and Cocurricular

Traditional Day Representative 2022

Achievements

- 300+ Leetcode problems
- 5th Rank in Technostorm code war
- Runner up in Kurukshetra2021.

•	Academic Topper Rank 1 in First year.